Many a times, you may wish to draw the attention of visitors to your website,
在许多情况下 你可能会希望引导正在浏览你页面的用户关注到
to certain parts of your website.
页面的某个特定部分
Or maybe you may want to deliver a message to users.
又或者你可能会想传递一些信息给用户
This is where the radius, available
这种时候 各种
mechanisms to deliver alerts to users, becomes very, very valuable.
可以用来“提醒”用户的技术就变得非常有用了
So in this lecture we will examine bootstrapped support for alerting users.
所以 在这一节课中 我们将会检视 Bootstrap 中有提醒用户功能的些许设计
We have labels, we have badges, we have alerts and progress bars.
它会涉及到标签 徽章 警告 进度条 等组件。
For simple updates to users labels and badges may be more than sufficient.
对于呈现给用户的一些简单更新 用标签和徽章可能就已经足够了
They just display a small piece of information within the website.
它们只需在网站里显示一小块信息
Say, for example, display the number of unread e-mails.
举个栗子 显示未读邮件的数目
Or maybe an item that is new or updated at this moment.
又或一个刚刚生成或更新的物件
These kind of things can easily be delivered using labels and badges.
这一类信息都可以轻松地用标签或徽章来传递
Alerts or error or warning messages can easily be delivered to users by
而 警告 / 错误 / 提醒 等需要重点强调的信息则可以
highlighting the messages on the website by surrounding it with appropriate
通过设置合适的背景
background so that it's clearly visible to the users.
来清晰地传递给用户
Progress bars are a way of indicating progress of any activity that is going on
进度条 顾名思义 是拿来显示你网站上 某种活动的进度的
on your website, like uploading or downloading a file for example.
比如说上传或者下载一个文件
Here is an example of the use of labels and badges on your website.
这里就是一个在你网站上使用标签和徽章的例子
Now, to use a label in bootstrap we will use the span tag and
为了在 Bootstrap 中使用标签 (label) 我们会用到 span 标签 (tag)
then apply the class label and depending on the color
同时 在设置 class="label" 后 还可以通过 继续设置类标签来得到你想要的颜色
that you want your label to be, you would use label primary info danger and so on.
比如说 label-primary 是深蓝色 label-info 是天蓝色 label-danger 是红色
And you can also specify the size of the label.
同时你还可以定制标签的大小 label-xs 之类的
Similarly, badges also use this span tag
类似的 徽章也是用 span 标签和 class=“badge”
with the class badge applied to the span tag.
来设置的
So as we have already seen Labels.
那么我们现在已经学习了
Use the class's label and label-color of
如何使用类标签来设置
the label that you want to use, and also the size.
你想要的特定颜色和大小的标签
Badges are fairly straightforward.
徽章则要简单明了得多
There's a single class called badge that you apply to the span tag, and
只用在 span 标签中设置 class="badge"
then whatever is the contents inside the span tags will be displayed as a badge.
就行了
The badge will automatically adapt to where it is displayed.
这么做了之后 徽章会自动适应它将要呈现的内容
So for example if the item for which it is included is with a darker background,
举个栗子 如果徽章要呈现的内容 有一个更深色的背景
the badge will be displayed in lighter color to match the other lettering
那么徽章将会用浅色
within within the parent tech.
来清晰呈现之
Badges are interesting in the sense that if there is no content within the badge,
徽章还有一个有趣的特性 当徽章中没有包含任何内容时
the badge just will automatically collapse.
徽章将会自动消失
So that it won't be visible on the screen.
也就是说屏幕上将看不到这个徽章
So that's one easy way of using badges on your website.
所以在你网站上用徽章是比较方便的 你不需要顾虑太多
Alerts are another way of delivering messages to the user.
警告 则是另外一个给用户传递信息的方法
An alert will be displayed at the location indicated within the webpage.
一个警告会在网页的一个特定位置显示
That alert will be surrounded by a bounding box
同时会被一个
with a background color that is determined by the specification.
特定颜色的“盒子”框住
So in this example, you see me saying alert warning.
在这个例子里 我指定的是 alert-warning 类
So that's why the background color is yellow in color.
所以我的背景颜色是黄色
In addition, within this alert, I am including the icon
特别地 在这个警告里我还用了一个图标 (icon)
the cross icon there which when clicked will dismiss the alert.
也就是这个小叉叉 我可以通过单击它来关闭这个警告
To make this work, of course, I need to include an icon for
当然了 为了让它起效果
that I am using the button tag.
我需要用一个 button tag 来实现
And inside the button tag I am applying the close class.
同时 我在 button 里面的设置了 class="close"
And also the class is displayed by using the times
以及设置了内容为 &times (也就是乘号) 符号
icon from HTML and for the alert itself,
注 这个乘号来自于 HTML 标准 可以自行谷歌 Html Entities
I need to apply the alert+dismissible class for this to work correctly.
除此之外 还需要给其添加 alert-dismissible 类
We can also include links within the messages that we displayed in the alerts,
我们还可以在警告中加进一个超链接
so in this example you see me using a link being displayed in the alert.
这个例子里 我就用了这么一个链接
So the links are actionable which means that the user can click on the link
当然这个链接是可操作的 所以用户点击它时
to perform the appropriate link action there.
它可以做出恰当的回应
As you saw in the example, the alert class is applied to the div.
你可能已经注意到 class="alert" 是被设置在 div 里面的
And inside there you can specify colors and also include links and
然后在这个 div 中 你可以设置颜色和链接
make the alert dismissible by including the cross button in the alert.
以及用一个小叉叉按钮来让这个警告可被关掉
For the dismissible action to work you need the JavaScript plug-in to be
为了真正实现关闭警告的操作
installed within your webpage.
必须在你的网页里安装相应的 JavaScript 插件
Finally, we have progress bars.
最后我们来看看进度条
Progress bars as I mentioned is a way of indicating progress of
进度条的功能是拿来显示
any action that is going on on a website.
任何网站中任务的进度
See, uploading a file or playing some music,
比如上传一个文件或播放一段音乐
whatever mechanism that you want to indicate the progress of the action
或任何其它你想要显示进度的操作
would be well shown on the webpage, using a progress bar.
都可以用进度条来漂亮地实现
To use a progress bar, you would use .
要使用一个进度栏你就用
And inside the div,
然后在这个 div 里面
you will have an inner div to which you will apply the progress bar class.
你需要再嵌套一个内部的 div 来设置 class="progress-bar"
The progress bar can also takes on the color
进度条 当然也可以设置颜色啦
representation using one of the standard colors there.
相应地使用如 progress-primary progress-danger 之类的标准色 你懂得
So that's why in this example you see me using progress bar danger.
这个例子里 我用的就是 progress-danger
You can also make the progress bar striped so you can apply the class
你还可以通过添加 progress-bar-striped 类 来给你的进度条带上条纹装饰
progress-bar-striped to make a striped class, if you don't apply that,
如果你不设置 progress-bar-striped
it'll be a solid color.
你的进度条将会是纯色的
The width of the progress bar is indicated by
进度条的进度
specifying the style for the progress bar.
可以通过 style 来控制
So in this case I'm specifying style="width:80%" so,
这个例子里我通过设置 style="width:80%"
that's why in the progress bar, 80% is covered.
来使这个进度条的进度为 80%
We can also include a text
我们还可以加进一些文本
that can be directly displayed inside the progress bar.
这些文本可以直接显示在进度条中
Now whatever we include in the span with the class sr-only Is meant for
注意这里的 span 里面的 sr-only 指的是
screen readers.
只有屏幕读取器才能看到的内容
So if screen readers are being used,
所以如果用户在使用屏幕读取器的话
then that information will be read out to the user.
span 里面那个 "80% Complete" 就会显示出来
We can also include the text directly in the progress bar, as you see,
当然了 正如你所见
using the 80% right in the example there.
直接键入 80% 也是可行的 它将会直接显示在进度条中
So, to use progress bars, we apply the progress class to an outer div and
总结一下 为了使用进度条 我们需要在一个 div 中 设置 class="progress"
then inside that we'll have an inner div that's a progress bar.
然后在这个 div 里 我们还需要嵌套一个 div 来设置各种属性
Now within the outer progress div you can have multiple progress bars, if you want.
注意到我们可以在最外层的 div 里面 同时设置很多个进度条
If you do include multiple progress bars, then they will be stacked so
然后如果你真的这么做了 你会发现它们将重叠在一起
you can create stacked progress bars if required.
所以你可以用这种方式来创建重叠进度条
And for a progress bar you can define the color and
需要记住的是 进度条是可以设置颜色
also whether it is striped or not.
以及条纹装饰的
You can even activate the animation of the striped
你甚至可以通过 active 类
display by using the active class for the progress bar.
来激活条纹进度条的动画效果
This completes our discussion on various ways of alerting users.
以上 我们完成了如何“提醒”用户的讨论
We'll now move on to a short exercise, where we will
接下来我们将会做一个小练习
look at the use of both labels and badges on our website.
去亲自在我们的网页中实现标签和徽章 【翻译 - Carefree0910 校对 - qiansen1386】